hotelogix.com 2019-05-20

# Hotelogix - Privacy Policies

### You own your data

HMS Infotech Pvt. Ltd, here after referred to as HMS, is an IT enabled company providing services & solution for the Hospitality & Travel Industry. Hotelogix is the name of the software owned by HMS. 

Hotelogix is a Web based Property Management System designed especially for small to mid size resorts/ businesses. Hotelogix is an solution is proposed to be a SAAS / custom service covering all the operational tasks including reservation, front desk, housekeeping transactions, accounts, back-office, MIS and other POS and further integrate all associated functions including marketing, bookings and business critical communication & coordination from multiple geographical locations seamlessly connected through the Net. 

HMS will only store information that is entered by the Users of an Organization, or automatically imported at a User’s instruction. The data entered, or imported on instruction, by the Users of an Organization remains the property of the Organization and HMS will not use nor make available for use any of this information without permission of the Organization.

### You control who has access to your data

The data entered, or imported on instruction, by the Users of an Organization is stored securely in a database and is only accessible to the approved Users of the Organization. The Administrator of the Organization (Administrator) will have full control over who is invited to be a User. A user name and password is required in order to access an Organization's information in HMS.

It is the User’s responsibility to keep their passwords safe. It is the Administrator’s responsibility to ensure that any Users that are invited to use the Organization’s account have permission to view the Organization’s information stored in the HMS account.

HMS, HMS’s staff and HMS’s partners do not have access to the User’s passwords and are therefore unable to access the Organization’s account or data without receiving an invitation from the Administrator.

### Legal basis for processing personal information (EEA visitors only)

HMS is respectful of data privacy and adopts best practice in compliance with applicable privacy law and regulations, including the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). The GDPR promotes fairness and transparency for all individuals in respect of their personal data. This privacy policy applies to all data we process, and by using HMS, you consent to our collection and use of such data.

If you reside in the European Union (EU), United Kingdom, Lichtenstein, Norway, Iceland or Switzerland, you may have additional rights with respect to your Personal Data. These rights may include rights under the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

If you are a customer located in the European Economic Area (EEA), HMS is the ‘data processor’ of your personal information and you are the ‘controller’ of your own data.

### Your responsibility as a customer

Within the scope of the agreement and in its use of the services, controller shall be solely responsible for complying with the statutory requirements relating to data protection and privacy, in particular regarding to the disclosure and transfer of personal data to the processor and the processing of personal data.

Controller is obliged to inform the processor without undue delay and comprehensively about any errors or irregularities related to statutory provisions on the processing of personal data.

### HMS responsibility

The parties acknowledge and agree that customer is the controller of personal data and HMS is the processor of that data. Processor shall collect, process and use personal data only within the scope of the controller’s Instructions. And you as the customer of HMS will be the controller of your data.

If the processor believes that an Instruction of the controller does not comply with the Data Protection Law, it shall immediately inform the controller without delay. If processor cannot process personal data in accordance with the instructions due to a legal requirement under any applicable European Union or Member State law, processor will promptly notify the controller of that legal requirement before the relevant processing to the extent permitted by the Data Protection Law.

If at any time you as a controller wish to opt out of any disclosures of your information to third parties or to prevent the use of your personal information for a purpose that is materially different from the purpose for which it was originally collected, you may log into your account and make necessary changes. The use of your information can be limited, or the information can be corrected, deleted, or exported to you or a third-party of your choice, as prescribed by the law indicated above.

### HMS monitors system usage

Length and Location of Stored Data: HMS will keep your data as it is obligated to keep it under the Data Retention laws in place in the country in which you access the service. If you are accessing this service in the EU, HMS will not transfer your data out of the EU, unless the third party is outside of the EU.

HMS’s Data Protection Officer is reachable here [gdpr@hotelogix.com](mailto:gdpr@hotelogix.com)

### Accessing the logs

_Access to the logs is restricted to verified HMS employees only.  _

### Your data is sent securely across the internet

HMS Servers have Thawte issued security certificates so all data transferred between the Users of an Organization and the HMS Servers is encrypted. However, the internet is not in itself a secure environment. Users should only enter, or instruct the importation of, data to the database within a secure environment. This means that the User’s browser must support the encryption security used in connection with the HMS Servers.

### HMS does not store your credit card details

If you choose to pay for HMS by Credit Card, your credit card details are not stored by HMS and cannot be accessed by HMS staff. Your credit card details are encrypted and securely stored by Direct Payment Solution to enable HMS to automatically bill your credit card on a recurring basis. 

### HMS will give you access to your data at any time

On request, HMS will provide the Administrator with a full export of the Organization’s data in a common file format determined by HMS. The Organization’s data may be permanently deleted by HMS 90 days after the Organization stops paying to use HMS, or at the Administrator’s request.

### Your browser stores only enough information to keep you logged in

HMS uses temporary cookies to keep a session open after a User logs in. These cookies do not contain any information about the User or the Organization and will automatically expire 45 minutes after the session is finished.

### Our policy toward children

We do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 (or under the age of 14 for anyone living in Spain or South Korea or under the age of 18 for anyone living in India) or knowingly allow such persons to register. If we become aware that we have collected personal information from a child under the relevant age without parental consent, we take steps to delete that information.

### Breach management

In the event of a system breach which leads to data theft, you may have an obligation to inform a supervisory authority, or to inform the data subjects involved.

HMS will notify you within 72 hours in the unlikely event that there is a breach of the cloud storage and will assist you in determining your notification obligations.

### This policy may be updated from time to time

HMS Infotech reserves the right to changes the privacy policy at any time by posting the revised privacy policy on the website. The revised privacy policy will be effective immediately upon posting on the website. We recommend you check this Privacy Policy frequently to stay abreast of any changes.

### Please read our Terms of Use

All use of software available on this website is subject to HMS’s terms of use. In the event of a conflict or disagreement between this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use, the Terms of Use will prevail.
